多一点血
More blood.
太棒了 继续加 再加一些
Great. Keep it coming. Chuck, Terry, pump away.
别那么小气
Don't be stingy.
小心那个手臂 我可以看到那个假手臂
Okay, watch that arm. I can see that fake arm.
契斯 让那个爪子继续动
Chase, keep that claw really moving.
杰佛瑞 像佛莱迪把它装上去 非常好
Jeffrey, jam it on there just like Freddy would. Good. Good.
卡 冲洗出来看一下
And cut. Print that, Gretchen.
谢谢 冲洗第七场就好
Thank you, sir. Printing seven only.
这让他之前的手爪看起来像是泰瑞莎修女的手套
You're a genius. This makes his old claw look like Mother Teresa's mitten.
谢谢它们吧 它们非常敏感
You better thank them, they're very sensitive.
- 查克 泰瑞 假血很不错 - 谢谢
- Chuck, Terry, great blood. - Thank you very much.
我的代表作
Some of our best work.
要看一些很酷的东西吗
Monkey man, wanna see some neat stuff?
- 是的 - 契斯
- Yeah! - Chase.
来吧
Oh, come on.
它只是做的很逼真
It's only make-believe.
- 玛莉安 我得走了 - 好的
- Marianne, I gotta go. - Okay.
低头
Low bridge.
来看看我们能不能找到一些东西好好吓一下妈妈
We'll see if we can't find someone's to scare the pj's off of Mommy.
海瑟
Hey, Heather.
你饿了吗 迪伦
You hungry, Dylan?
骗到你了
Ooh, gotcha.
它的反射动作应该更好
It should have flexed more.
契斯 假血让伺服器短路
Chase, I think the servos got shorted out with blood.
把它拆掉 拿出伺服器 用保丽龙包好
Well, take it apart, pull it out, and insulate them with some styro.
它不应该沾到血的
Thing wasn't meant to be submerged, for Pete's sake.
我不喜欢那个东西
I don't like that thing.
它让我们全家不致于饿肚子
It puts bread on our table.
它是真的吗 爸爸
Is it alive, Daddy?
海瑟 接下来轮到你了
Heather, you're in the next shot.
先进机器人设计 使用生物有机外皮
State-of-the-art animatronics enhanced with bio-organic grafting.
牛腱组织
Bull tendons.
- 杜宾狗的神经束 - 契斯
- Nerve bundles from a live Doberman. - Chase.
哇啊
Whoa.
哇 查克
Shit, Chuck!
它应该是接收到对讲机讯号
Uh, it must have picked up a signal from an AD's walkie-talkie.
- 你确定关了吗 - 我把它关掉了
- You sure it's turned off? - It's off.
它是温的 跟真的手一样
It's funny, it's warm, just like a real hand.
天啊
Oh, God.
发生了什么事 关掉特效
What the hell is going on? Cut the effects!
契斯
Chase!
泰端 它在哪里
Terry, where is it?
泰端
Terry!
放开我
Chuck, get off me!
海瑟
Heather!
- 海瑟 它在哪里 - 契斯 它在哪里
- Heather, where is it? - Chase, where the hell is it?
迪伦
Dylan!
来吧
Come on!
怎么会这样
What the fuck?
迪伦
Dylan.
契斯 不
Chase! No!
是地震 来吧
Earthquake. Come on.
妈妈
Mommy!
迪伦
Dylan!
Dylan! Dylan!
迪伦
Dylan!
那是什么声音
What is that?
汽车防盗器
Car alarms.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
你没事吧 儿子
You okay, chief?
- 不 - 嘿嘿
- No. - Heh, heh.
- 甜心 你发烧了吗 - 只是地震而已 迪伦
- Honey, do you have a fever? - Just another earthquake, Dylan.
- 很好玩吧 - 爸爸 你流血了
- Getting kind of fun, huh? - Daddy, blood.
没事的 各位
It's nothing, guys.
只是擦伤 真的
It's a scratch. Really.
你怎么受伤的
Where did you get that?
我想是被掉下来的照片弄伤的
I don't know. Picture, I guess. The one that fell.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
包扎一下就好
Put a bandage on it.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
加州理工学院的地质学家确认
Geologists at Caltech have confirmed...
- 今天早上的余震 - 我们非看那个不可吗
- ...that this morning's aftershock.... - Do we have to watch that?
(地震探测)
- 是你把电视打开的 - 对已经受损的停车场结构
- You turned it on. - It caused further collapse...
造成进一步伤害
...of the already badly damaged parking structure....
我去把它关掉
I'll turn it off.
这很正常 上星期发生的强震
This is normal, following a quake of last week's magnitude...
规模是六点八级
...now thought to be a massive 6. 8.
迪伦 这是早餐 不是美术课时间
Dylan, this is breakfast, not arts and crafts.
什么
What?
昨晚你有睡吗
Did you get any sleep last night?
睡了一下
More or Iess.
好吧 该换衣服了 我会迟到的
Okay, time to get dressed. I'm late.
你要出门
You're going away?
我只离开几小时 茱莉会来陪你
Just for a few hours. Julie will be with you.
有其他的事困扰着你吗
Is there anything other than the obvious bothering you?
三周内发生五次地震 真的够严重了 甜心
I think five earthquakes in three weeks is enough, sweetie.
你该不会又接到电话了吧
Hasn't been another phone call, has there?
不是的
No.
那是个好迹象 他消失了两个星期
Good sign. Two full weeks without him.
或许他被卡车撞死了
Maybe he got hit by a truck.
我觉得他是更加接近
He's closer, if anything.
这让我做恶梦 契斯
It's giving me nightmares, Chase.
昨晚你做了恶梦
Did you have one last night?
只是地震而已 海瑟
Ah, it's just the earthquakes, Heather.
或许是吧
Maybe.
或许今天我不该接受访问
Maybe I shouldn't do this interview today.
不 你总得恢复正常生活
No. You've gotta get back on the horse sometime.
听着 有个疯子打骚扰电话给你
Look, you had a nutcase making harassing phone calls.
- 我知道那有多可怕 - 不 你不了解
- I know how scary that's been. - No, you don't.
好吧 我是不了解
Okay. I don't.
但那不代表我们不能忘了这一切
But it doesn't mean that it can't be over.
如果一切还没有结束呢
Yeah, but what if it isn't over?
或许你该跟我谈谈你的梦
Maybe you should tell me your dream.
真的没什么
Oh, it was nothing. It was....
你跟我合拍电影 我们终于一起合作
You and I were working on this movie, together for once...
你做的特效出了间题
...and one of your special effects went really wrong.
查克跟泰瑞受伤
And Chuck and Terry got hurt...
你的手指被切断
...and, heh, well, your fingers were cut.
就像这样
Right here?
海瑟 或许你是半梦半醒
Heather, you were probably half-awake...
看到我的手指 被掉下来的镜子割伤 梦就是那样
...and saw my fingers get nicked when the mirror fell. Dreams are like that.
听着 如果你不要我接下这份工作 我可以放弃
Look, if you don't want me to go on this job, I won't.
小心点 好吗
Pfft! Just be careful, okay?
我可以到棕榈泉待两天
I think I can survive two days in Palm Springs...
为体香剂广告做泡泡特效 你觉得呢
...supplying soap bubbles for a detergent commercial, don't you?
我想是吧
I guess so.
- 你想是吧 - 嗯
- You guess so? - Yeah.
过来
Come here.
48小时
Mmm. Forty eight hours.
我会准时回来
I'll be back in no time.
- 我得走了 - 好的
- I gotta go. - Okay.
嘿
Hey!
我喜欢你的设计
I love what you've done with the place.
给他们好看
Knock them dead.
迪伦 我得走了 好好照顾妈妈
Dylan, I gotta go! Take care of Mommy.
拜
Bye.
南希
Nancy.
迪伦
Dylan.
南希
Nancy.
迪伦 我不要你看这个
Dylan, I don't want you watching this.
什么 怎么了 你是怎么了
What? What's wrong? What's gotten into you?
哈罗
Hello?
一 二
One, two...
- 哈罗 - 佛莱迪要来抓你了
- Hello? - Freddy's coming for you!
契斯
Chase!
我觉得不太对劲
Someone's coming.
什么
What?
- 你没事吧 甜心 - 没事
- Are you okay, honey? - Yes.
海瑟
Heather!
理
Hey.
没事吧
Is everything okay?
没事 只是地震 刚刚你感觉到地震了吗
Yeah. Just these quakes. Did you feel a little one just now?
不 只是一辆卡车经过
Oh, no. A truck went by right before you opened the door.
他们在抢修水管
That's life on the fault line.
- 宝贝 - 茱莉
- Hey, tiger. - Hi, Julie.
你觉得他烫烫的吗 今天早上他发烧了
Does he feel warm to you? He had a fever this morning, I think.
不 他没事
Hmm. No. He seems okay.
你确定只是那样
Are you sure that's all that's wrong? You seem...
别来烦我们 你这个混蛋
Leave us alone, you son of a bitch!
洛杉矶礼车公司
L.A. Limousine, ma'am.
小姐 我已经到了
Just wanted you to know I'm out front.
对不起 你能等一下吗
I'm sorry! Can you hang on a minute?
海瑟
Heather.
- 怎么了 - 我不知道
- What is it? - I don't know.
今天我觉得怪怪的
I just have this weird feeling today.
妈妈
Mommy...
- 那么待在家里 - 迪伦
- ...stay home, then. - Dylan.
打骚扰电话的家伙
This damn caller.
他又来了
He started again?
大变态
Sick fuck.
抱歉
Sorry.
迪伦应该没发烧
You know, Dylan doesn't seem to have a fever.
或许是你太紧张了
It's probably just your nerves.
紧张
Nerves?
我是说因为早上发生地震
I just meant from the shaker this morning.
大家都吓坏了 最近老是发生地震
I mean, everybody's freaked out about how many we've been having.
加上那些骚扰电话
And then these phone calls.
别接
Don't answer it.
- 喂 - 对不起 小姐
- Hello? - Excuse me, ma'am...
- 我们要迟到了 - 好吧
- ...but we are going to be late. - Okay.
迪伦
Dylan?
我得走了 你能原谅我吗
I gotta go. Forgive me?
再见
Bye.
我会帮你打电话报警 我的联络方式在冰箱上 好吗
I'll, uh, call the cops for you. You've got the number on the fridge, right?
他们打电话来时告诉他们 他们应该会追踪这件事
Just give them the time they called and they're keeping this list, supposedly.
茱莉
Oh, Julie.
对不起 我太神经兮兮了
I'm really sorry. My nerves are a little raw.
没关系的
It's okay.
对 我得挂电话了
Yeah. I gotta go.
- 早安 - 早安
- Morning. - Good morning.
你饰演那个女孩
You play that girl?
在那部电影里 那个有怪手的家伙
In that movie. With the guy with the pfft!
没错 就是你
Yeah, sure. That's you.
这就是我喜欢这份工作的原因 我可以看到大明星
Ah, that's what I love about this job. I get to meet the stars.
我不算是明星
I'm hardly a star.
什么 你在开玩笑吗
What? Are you kidding?
我喜欢你的作品
I love your stuff.
第一集最精彩
The first was the best.
你的姊妹淘被开肠剖肚 还被人拖过天花板
Your girlfriend's cut open and dragged across the ceiling.
那真的是太恐怖了
It was awesome.
你男朋友的床开始喷血
When that blood comes out of your boyfriend's bed?
我被吓到了
Yeah, I thought I'd shit.
他们不该杀死佛莱迪的
But they never should have killed off Freddy!
海瑟 听着 我们得快一点
Heather, look, we gotta go! Let's go!
你差点就迟到了 你想害我被开除吗
Come on. Cutting it close, aren't you? Trying to get me fired?
好吧 我们来了
Okay, okay, okay! We're coming!
我们来了 不
We're coming. No! No! No!
海瑟 《半夜鬼上床》系列
So, Heather, we're approaching the 10th anniversary...
即将要欢庆 十周年纪念
...of this Nightmare on Elm Street thing.
第一集跟后面的五集续集非常地受欢迎
I mean the original five very popular sequels.
这样的成功纪录 对你个人有什么影响
How has all this success affected you personally?
我不知道它有没有影响 山姆
Well, I don't know if it really has, Sam. Oh, God.
除了第一集跟第三集 我没有参与其他的续集演出
With the exception of 1 and 3, I pretty much stayed out of it.
现在我拍电视影集
You know, I'm doing a lot more television now.
花很多时间陪我丈夫跟儿子
Those hours let me spend more time with my husband and my little boy.
没错 你有个儿子 他叫什么名字
That's right, you have a little boy. What's his name?
迪伦
Dylan.
生下迪伦让你改变了
With Dylan, does that change your feeling,
你对恐怖电影的看法吗
your perspective about horror movies?
不 完全不会
No, not really.
我是说你会让他看 你拍的电影吗
Would you let him see one of your movies?
我儿子 不会
My son? Heh, no.
我相信大家常问你这个问题
I'm sure people always ask you this all the time.
你们会再拍续集吗
Is there going to be another sequel?
还有佛莱迪真的死了吗
And what's more, is Freddy really dead?
当然他死了 佛莱迪已经消失
Of course he is. Freddy's dead and gone.
跟你合演第一集的演员呢
How about your co-star in the original, in Nightmare 1?
你会让他跟迪伦独处吗
Would you trust him alone with Dylan?
劳勃 我不知道
Robert? Heh. I don't know.
为什么我们不问问他呢
Why don't we ask him how he'd feel about it?
我们为你与观众准备了一个惊喜
We've got a big surprise for you, Heather. And for our audience.
欢迎他出场 他是最受欢迎的恶鬼
Let's bring him out, he is the best of the bad.
欢迎劳勃英格朗
Let's say hello to Robert Englund!
我爱你 宝贝
Love you, babe!
我们一起吃午餐吧
We'll do lunch! Ha!
好吧
All right! Yeah!
佛莱迪回来了 欢迎佛莱迪叔叔
Freddy's back! Give it up for your Uncle Freddy!
你以为你终于可以好好睡一觉了
Just when you thought it was safe to get back into bed!
跟我击掌吧
Give me five!
我回来了 我比以前更坏
I'm back and I'm badder than ever!
佛莱迪
Freddy! Freddy! Freddy!
现在你们都是我的孩子
Ha! You are all my children now!
- 我们得走了 劳勃 - 等一下 我送你
- We've gotta go, Robert. - Um, just a second. I'll walk you.
- 来吧 孩子 - 谢谢
- There you go, Christy. - Thank you!
- 再见 - 谢谢
- Bye-bye! - Thank you!
- 你没事吧 - 我很好
- You okay? - I'm fine.
一切都很好
I don't know. Everything went great, I thought.
- 我们真的吓到你了吧 - 我不知道为什么你不告诉我
- We really got you, didn't we? - I don't know why you didn't tell me.
他们喜欢你的表情
Come on, they loved the expression on your face.
- 他们希望我们能再度合作 - 拍浪漫喜剧
- They'd like to see us together again. - ln what, a romantic comedy?
即使是爱情故事
Just because it's a love story
不代表我们不能砍掉几个人的头
doesn't mean you can't have a decapitation or two.
- 海瑟 找你的电话 - 我的
- Heather, there's a call for you. - For me?
- 再聊吧 - 再见
- Listen, I'll talk to you later. Bye-bye. - Bye-Bye.
喂
Hello?
海瑟 我是新线影业的莎拉·瑞雪
Heather, it's Sara Risher over at New Line Cinema.
你好吗
How are you?
嗨 莎拉 你好 好久不见
Hi, Sara. How are you? This is a voice from the past.
我只会耽误你一下
It sure is. Well, listen, Heather, I won't take but a minute.
我们有份工作要跟你谈
It's just that we have something to propose to you...
不知道你能不能到办公室来一趟 巴伯想跟你谈
...and I wonder if you'd stop by the offices. Bob would love to talk to you.
没问题 什么时候
Well, sure. When?
择日不如撞日 礼车会送你过来
No time like the present. The car will bring you over.
- 现在吗 - 一下子就好
- Now? - Just take a minute.
你会很高兴你决定这么做的 再见
You'll be glad you did, I bet. Bye.
- 需要我效劳吗 - 我来找巴伯·夏伊
- Can I help you? - I'm here to see Bob Shaye.
巴伯跟你有约吗
Was Bob expecting you?
- 海瑟 - 莎拉 你好吗
- Heather? Hi. - Sara, how are you?
- 我很好 你呢 - 很高兴能见到你
- I'm fine. How are you? - Great to see you.
- 你看起来好漂亮 - 谢谢
- You look great. - Thank you.
巴伯在等你
Bob is dying to see you.
- 你要喝点东西吗 - 咖啡就好了
- Can I get you something to drink? - Coffee would be fine.
- 黑咖啡好吗 - 好的
- Black? - Black's fine.
金 麻烦帮我们倒咖啡
Kim, could you get us some coffee?
- 好的 - 谢谢
- Sure. - Thanks.
我觉得那家伙是混蛋
I think the guy's a little bit of a jerk...
但看到剧本才能知道
...but we won't know until we've read the script.
好吧 我拿到剧本再打电话给你
Anyhow, I'll give you a call when...
听着 我得挂电话了
Hey! Listen, man, I gotta go.
- 谢谢 - 到米兰后打电话给我
- Thanks. - Call me when you get to Milan.
别忘了意式炖饭小馆
And don't forget, risotto con tartufo. It's fantastico.
保重 再见
Take care, man. I'll talk to you later. Bye.
天啊 你看起来好漂亮 海瑟 你好吗
Boy, do you look great, Heather. How are you?
我很好
Great. I'm fine.
我不必问你过得好不好
I don't have to ask how you're doing.
目前为止还不错
Well, so far, so good.
所以今天我们请你过来
Which, by the way, is why we asked you to come by today.
- 谢谢你 金 - 不客气
- Ah, thanks, Kim. - Sure.
海瑟 我就直说了
Look, Heather, let me cut to the chase.
你要加入我们回到恶梦里吗
How would you like to join us in the definitive Nightmare?
我以为你们杀死佛莱迪了
I thought you killed Freddy off.
没错 但影迷
Well, we did, but the fans...
上帝保佑他们 他们想再看到续集
You know, the fans, God bless them, they're clamoring for more.
我想邪恶力量不死
I guess evil never dies, right?
总之几星期前威斯打电话给我
Anyhow, a few weeks ago I got a call from Wes...
他提出一个非常棒的点子
...and he pitched me this really exciting idea.
我心想"有谁比原创者 更适合让佛莱迪复活"
I started thinking, "Who better to resurrect Freddy than his creator? "
威斯不再拍恐怖电影
Well, I thought Wes stopped doing horror movies.
他说十年来他不跟我联络
Do you know he actually told me he hadn't called in the last 10 years...
因为他一直没有 再做可怕的恶梦
...because he hadn't had any really scary nightmares.
它们是这个系列的灵感来源
They're his inspiration for this thing.
总之他正在写剧本
Anyhow, he's right in the middle of the script.
代表他又开始做恶梦了
Which means he's having nightmares again.
他真的很兴奋
Well, he's very excited about it.
- 关于恶梦 - 不 甜心 关于剧本
- The nightmares? - No, sweetie, the script.
你也该觉得兴奋 因为你是主角
And you should be too, because you're the star.
我不知道 巴伯
I don't know, Bob.
我真的是受宠若惊
I'm flattered, really.
- 但现在我有孩子了 - 所以呢
- But I have a kid now and... - Well, so?
我不想再拍恐怖片
So I'm not sure about doing horror.
少来了 海瑟 小孩子喜欢恐怖片
Oh, come on, Heather. Kids love horror.
谢谢你 巴伯
Thank you so much, Bob.
我有其他的计划
I have other things happening.
我们会出一样的价钱
I promise you we'll match any offer that's on the table.
不 不是那样的
No. It's not that.
我有个影迷
Look, I have a fan.
海瑟 你有很多影迷 我们一直在对你做行销研究
You've got plenty of fans. We've been doing marketing research on you.
你的支持度非常高
You are rating right up there.
契斯一直在做新手套设计
We've got Chase working on a prototype for the new glove.
- 它真的 - 什么
- It's really... - What?
我们请他保密 想给你一个惊喜
Okay, I know, we asked him to keep it as a surprise...
让我可以亲自跟你谈
...until you and I could have this conversation.
巴伯
Bob...
威斯开始写剧本多久了
...how long has Wes been working on this script?
有几个月了 为什么
I don't know. A couple months. Why?
你开始考虑拍续集后 有发生奇怪的事吗
Since you've been thinking of making it, has anything funny happened?
- 你是什么意思 - 譬如说奇怪的电话
- What do you mean? - Well, like weird phone calls?
或是做恶梦
Or nightmares?
你何不接电话 巴伯
Why don't you answer your phone, Bob?
我花钱雇人帮我接电话
Come on. That's what we've got people we pay around here for.
有人接电话吗
Will someone pick up the damn phone?
- 谢谢 - 不客气
- Thanks a lot. - You're welcome.
迪伦
Dylan?
永远不要睡
Never sleep again.
发生了什么事
What is going on?
你该不会让他看电视播出的老电影吧
You didn't let him watch the movie on TV, did you?
电影 他根本没看电视
Movie? He didn't watch anything on TV.
他在睡午觉 我听到他大叫
He was taking his nap, and I heard him screaming.
甜心 你没事吧
Honey, are you okay?
雷斯救了我
Mm-hm. Rex saved me.
是吗
He did?
雷斯会死吗
Is Rex going to die?
不
No!
雷斯不会死
Rex is not going to die.
我跟你保证 甜心
I promise you, sweetie.
你知道针线放在厨房的什么地方吗
Do you know where the sewing stuff is in the kitchen?
当然
Sure.
我们要动手术了 好吗 来吧
We'll do an operation, okay? Come on.
迪伦医生 茱莉医生
Dr. Dylan and Dr. Julie.
修好了就会像新的一样
Fix him up good as new, okay? Okay.
契斯 找你的电话 你太太打来的
Hey, Chase, you got a call! It's your wife.
- 海瑟 - 契斯 你得赶快回家
- Heather. - Chase, hi. You better come home.
海瑟 我真的很忙
Oh, Heather, I'm stuck here.
今天查克跟泰瑞都没出现
Neither Chuck or Terry came in today.
怎么了 发生了什么事
Why? What's the matter?
- 契斯 是迪伦 - 什么
- Chase, it's Dylan. - What?
等一下 我听不清楚
Hold on. The phone's breaking up.
迪伦怎么了
Okay. What's going on with Dylan?
他发作了
He's had some sort of an episode.
什么 什么发作
What? What kind of episode?
他的行为非常奇怪
He was just acting very strangely...
像是有人在追他
...Iike somebody was after him.
好可怕 我被吓到了
It's scary. It scared me.
- 他好像 - 什么
- He was acting like.... - Like what?
他好像佛莱迪
Like Freddy.
海瑟 你又接到骚扰电话了
Heather, has there been another phone call?
为什么你不告诉我你在设计新手套
Chase, why didn't you tell me you were working on a new glove?
为什么今天查克跟泰瑞没有去上班
And why aren't Chuck and Terry at work today?
别管那些混蛋了 回答我
Forget those clowns, Heather. Answer me.
你是不是又接到骚扰电话了
Has there been another phone call today or not?
对
Yes.
好吧
Okay.
我立刻回家 我三小时后到
I'm coming home. I'll be there in three hours.
丹尼 我得走了
Danny, I gotta go.
- 怎么了 - 我儿子生病 我得走了
- What's up, Chase? - My kid's sick. I gotta fly.
太阳一下山
"As soon as the sun was up...
巫婆要葛丽泰捡木柴生火
...the witch made Gretel fetch wood and kindle a fire.
我们要先烤饼干
"We will bake cookies first," she said.
我们要加热烤箱跟揉面团
"I've heated the oven and kneaded the dough.
用手试试火是不是够大
Crawl in and see if the fire is blazing high enough now."
她把葛丽泰朝烤箱雅
As she pushed Gretel toward the oven...
女巫想关上烤箱的门烧死她
...the witch meant to shut the door and bake her once she was inside."
迪伦 这太暴力了
Dylan, this is so violent.
我不知道为什么 你喜欢这些愚蠢的童话故事
I don't know why you like these stupid old fairy tales.
请念完
Finish, please.
它们会害你做恶梦的
They're gonna give you nightmares.
我喜欢这个故事
I like this story.
葛丽泰知道巫婆想做什么
"But Gretel guessed what the witch was planning.
我该怎么办呢
"I don't know how to get in," Gretel said. "How am I to manage it?"
巫婆大叫着"愚蠢的女孩 快点进烤箱"
"Stupid girl," shouted the witch rushing up to the oven.
"烤箱门够大了 看吧 连我都进得去"
"The opening is big enough. See, I can fit myself."
葛丽泰很快地从后面一推
Then quickly, Gretel came behind and pushed with all her might...
把巫婆往大火里推
...plunging the wicked old woman headlong into the flames...
关上烤箱门后锁紧
...banging the door shut and bolting it tight.
巫婆大声叫着
The witch howled."
够了
That's enough.
巫婆跟抓狂的猫一样大叫着
"The witch howled like a scalded cat...
葛丽泰看着她活活被烧死
...but Gretel ran and left her there to perish nonetheless.
她跑去救她哥哥
She ran to her brother as fast as she could and flung open the door.
她哭着说"汉瑟 我们得救了 巫婆死了"
"Hansel! Hansel!" she cried, "We're saved! The witch is dead!"
该睡觉了
Time for sleep.
告诉我他们怎么找到回家的路
Say how they find their way back home.
明晚再说
Tomorrow night.
不 今晚就说
No. Tonight.
那真的很重要
It's important.
迪伦 你知道他们跟着面包屑
Dylan, you know as well as I do.
找到回家的路
They follow the trail of bread crumbs back to their house.
他们的爸爸拼命地亲吻他们
And then their father covered them with kisses and they were safe.
他们平安无事 可以好好睡着了
They were safe and they could sleep. Now, come on.
- 那是什么 - 雷斯
- What is that? - Rex.
来吧
Come on.
雷斯把他困在下面
Rex keeps him down there.
谁
Who?
有爪子的凶老头
The mean old man with the claws.
他趁着我们睡着时想爬上来
He wants to come up while we sleep.
我把脚放在这里
I keep my feet up here.
雷斯把他困在下面
Rex keeps him down there.
它是我的警卫
He's my guard.
你也该找个警卫
You should have a guard too.
迪伦 下面没有东西
Dylan, there's nothing down there.
来
Come here.
看吧
Look. See?
你不在时不是这样
It's different when you're gone.
睡觉吧
Come on.
拜托别关
On, please.
好吧 宝贝
Okay, sweetie.
好好睡吧
Night, night. Sleep tight.
别被虫子咬了
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
爸爸会回家吗
Daddy coming home?
他已经在回家的路上了
He's on his way.
他会跟着面包屑回家吧
He can follow the bread crumbs, right?
没错
Right.
如果面包屑没先被小鸟吃掉
If the birds don't eat them first.
这是怎样
Ah, perfect, perfect, perfect.
快点
Come on. Come on. Come on.
那是角落里的我
That's me in the corner.
那是照明灯里的我
That's me in the spotlight.
灯光
Light
失去我的
Losin' my...
宗教信仰
...religion.
妈 你害怕吗
Mommy's scared?
迪伦
Dylan.
妈妈没事
Mommy's fine.
我只是做了恶梦
It was just a bad dream.
你怎么醒了
What are you doing out of bed?
雷斯叫醒我 它在战斗
Rex woke me up. He was fighting.
迪伦 快回去睡吧
Dylan, go back to sleep, honey.
我睡不着
I'm not sleepy.
哈罗
Hello?
我们是警察 女士 请开门
Police, ma'am. Can you open the door?
你是海瑟·兰根坎普
Heather Langenkamp?
对
Yes?
契斯·波特是你丈夫
Is Chase Porter your husband?
对
Yes.
很遗憾发生了意外
I'm afraid there was an accident.
看起来他在开车时睡着了
It appears he fell asleep while driving, ma'am.
他 我是说
Is he... I mea...
他受伤了吗
Is he hurt?
恐怕情况要严重多了 女士
I'm afraid it's worse than that, ma'am.
他死了吗
Is he dead?
是的 女士
Yes, ma'am.
你们确定真的是他
Are you sure it's him?
我们找到他的证明 你可以确认一下
We have his effects. You can confirm from that.
我要认尸
I wanna see his body.
不 女士 你不必那么做
No, you don't, ma'am. It's not necessary.
我要亲眼看到他的尸体
I want to see it for myself.
对不起
Ahem. Excuse me.
- 需要我效劳吗 - 波特
- Can I help you? - Porter.
契斯·波特
Chase Porter.
他在这边
It's back here.
契斯吗
You said Chase?
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
请在下面签个名 那样子就可以了
Just sign here at the bottom. That's all we need.
我要再看一次
I'd like to see once again.
你说什么
I'm sorry?
你能再把床单拉起来一次吗
Could you lift the sheet again, please?
多拉开一些 拜托
More, please?
那是怎么一回事
What is that?
车子撞得稀烂
It was a bad wreck, ma'am.
我们会为葬礼把尸体处理好 可是
The head's gonna be all right for the funeral and all, but...
来吧 小姐 你没事吧
Here, lady. You okay?
- 你确定 - 对
- You sure? - Yes.
那是什么原因造成的
Oh, God. What did that?
车子被撞得稀烂
Well, they said the truck was tore up something awful.
你可以想像他不是
So you can imagine him not being in...
尸体的状况不太好
...well, exactly top shape.
那看起来像是
It Iooks Iike...
有人抓伤他
...he was clawed.
没错
Yeah.
所以我们不想掀开床单
Well, that's why we don't lift the sheet...
只让你看他的脸 女士
...past the face, ma'am.
有时候看到尸体的惨状 晚上我们会睡不着
Sometimes it's what we don't see that gets us through the night.
麻烦你签个名
So, uh, if you'll just sign....
上帝是我们的希望跟力量
God is our hope and strength...
在困难时唯一的帮手
...a very present help in trouble.
所以我们不害怕 即使大地为之震撼
Therefore, we will not fear, though the earth be moved...
即使高山沉入海底
...and though the hills be carried into the midst of the sea...
即使恶浪不断扑来
...though the waters thereof rage and swell...
即使高山崩塌
...and though the mountains shake at the tempest of the same...
快看
Look!
茱莉 迪伦在哪里
Julie, where's Dylan?
我不知道
I don't know.
妈妈
Help! Mommy!
迪伦
Dylan!
- 妈妈 - 迪伦
- Mommy! - Dylan!
迪伦 抓住妈妈的手
Dylan! Grab Mommy's hand!
抓紧了
Grab it!
天啊
Oh, my God!
快点
Hurry!
快来陪我
Stay with me.
快来陪我 海瑟
Stay with me, Heather.
不
No!
- 迪伦在哪里 - 他没事 他在这里
- Where's Dylan? Where's Dylan? - He's all right. He's right here.
- 发生了什么事 - 只是地震
- Oh, what happened? - lt was an earthquake.
你被震倒了
You got knocked off your feet.
事实上你受伤了
You got a pretty good bump, actually.
希望他能安息 孩子们
May he rest in peace, children...
希望你们都能平安回家
...and may you all get home safely.
阿门
Amen.
如果需要我帮忙 海瑟 什么事都可以
If there's anything I can do, Heather. Anything.
谢谢你 劳勃
Thank you, Robert.
甜心
Sweetie?
蒂娜
Tina?
迪伦
Dylan.
蒂娜
Tina?
你是谁
Who are you?
迪伦
Dylan.
宝贝 醒一醒
Baby, wake up.
迪伦 宝贝
Dylan! Dylan! Dylan, honey.
来吧
Come on.
我们得回去睡觉
Okay, sugar. We're gonna go back to bed now.
不 我在那里睡不着
No, Mommy, I can't sleep there.
你必须睡觉
Honey, you have to sleep.
一 二 佛莱迪要来抓你了
One, two, Freddy's coming for you
你在哪里听到那个的 你看电影学的吗
Where did you hear that? Did you hear that on that movie?
你有接电话吗
Did you answer the phone?
迪伦 你在哪里听到那首歌的
Dylan, where did you hear that song?
在我的床上
In my bed.
在你的床上
In your bed?
在我的床单下 孩子们在唱歌
Under my covers. Kids singing.
在下面 那个人
And way down there, the man...
那个很凶的人
...the mean man....
那个人在做什么
What is that man doing?
他想爬上床
Trying to get up.
他想进入我们的世界
Trying to get up into our world.
迪伦
Dylan.
爸爸在哪里
Where is Daddy now?
爸爸在天堂里
Daddy's in heaven.
他跟上帝在一起
He's with God now.
人得死掉才能见到上帝吗
Do you have to die to see God?
我不那么认为
I don't think so.
我想你必须祈祷
I think you have to pray.
跟社求救
And reach out.
为什么上帝要让不好的事发生
Why does God let there be bad things?
我真的不知道 甜心
I honestly don't know, honey.
拜托你睡一下吧
Please try to get some sleep.
你能跟我进入我的梦里吗
Can you come with me in my dreams?
我想那种事只会在电影里发生
I think that only happens in the movies.
但你回来时 我一定会在
But I'll always, always, be right here when you get back.
我保证不会让任何人
And I'll make sure...
伤害到你
...that nobody gets your toes.
我知道他的行为很古怪
I know his behavior is bizarre.
但通常他很正常 约翰
But he's usually so normal and well adjusted, John.
我不敢相信这是他 他没有受到任何影响
I just can't believe it's him and not something outside influencing him.
或许他是处在否认期
Or is that how denial works?
我不认为他是处在否认期
Whether it is denial, I don't think that's the case here.
如果你真的很担心迪伦 请医生帮他检查一下
Look, if you're really worried about Dylan, have a doctor check him out.
你可以相信一切都会没事的
You'll see. Everything's fine.
你那么说该不会是要安慰一个发疯的朋友吗
You're not just saying that to help a crazy friend cope, are you?
迪伦出现的种种行为
Everything about Dylan's behavior is understandable...
对一个刚刚失去的孩子来说是很正常的
...for a kid who just lost his father.
小孩子该怎么面对 那样的悲剧
How does a child process a thing like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也一直无法好好面对
I've not been able to process it very well myself.
你没有发疯
And you're not crazy, by the way.
看到佛莱迪出现在坟墓里感觉真的很疯狂 又跳进去
Seeing Freddy in that grave feels pretty crazy, and then jumping in.
- 你没跳进去 - 在我记忆里是的
- You didn't jump in. - That's my memory.
感觉真的很真实
It seemed absolutely real.
那是感觉 不是事实
Seemed, not was.
那是
It's....
那是我家族的遗传
It's in my family, you know.
怎么了
What is?
我的一个近亲在精神病院过世
A very close relative died in an institution.
真的吗 如果家族有精神病史可以让一个人发疯
Really? Well, if having a screwy family made a person crazy...
这个世界早成了疯人院
...the whole world would be one big loony bin.
有个疯子在骚扰你
You have a crazed fan after you.
那足以把你逼疯 或许对迪伦来说也一样
That's what's making you crazy, and probably Dylan too.
- 我不曾跟他提过那件事 - 孩子们知道
- I never mentioned that to him. - Kids know.
他们知道有事让父母觉得不安
Kids know when something's bugging a parent.
你仍不知道是谁打电话骚扰你
You have no idea who this is calling?
我只知道他是佛莱迪
Freddy, for all I know.
少来了
Come on.
这个男人
It's a man...
或声音低沉的男孩
...or a boy, with a deep, you know...
模仿佛莱迪的声音
...Freddy voice.
长达六个星期 你很讶异 你会梦到佛莱迪
Six weeks of this, and you're surprised you've got Freddy in your dreams?
该死 被骚扰的人
Hell, Sonny Bono...
很容易疑神疑鬼
...after a while began seeing his stalker everywhere, even at Mass.
真的吗
Really?
赖特曼报警多少次
And how many times did Letterman call the cops thinking that woman...
- 宣称那个女人又跑到他的厨房里 - 是的
- ...was down in the kitchen again? - Yeah.
它会弄得你神经兮兮 如果你 如果你让它那么做
I mean, it gets under your skin if you.... If you let it.
你真的认为迪伦没事
You really think Dylan's okay?
迪伦没事 你没事
Dylan's fine. You're fine.
你很难过 但你没事 你也没发疯
You're hurting but you're fine, and you're definitely not crazy.
我最担心的事
My worst fear...
就是我家里的疯狂基因遗传到我身上
...that whatever madness is in my family I have.
我又遗传给迪伦
That I've passed it on to Dylan.
迪伦
Dylan!
- 海瑟 - 迪伦
- Heather! - Dylan!
- 确定他没事 约翰 - 你没事吧
- Make sure he's okay, John! - Yeah, are you all right?
- 你受伤了吗 - 天哪
- Are you okay, huh? - Oh, my God.
- 你受伤了吗 - 迪伦 你没事吧 甜心
- Are you sure? Does anything hurt? - Dylan, are you all right? Honey?
你没事吧
Are you all right? Are you sure?
上帝不肯收我
God wouldn't take me.
噢 天啊 喔 宝贝
Oh, my God. Oh, honey.
不可思议
It's unbelievable.
- 哪位 - 劳勃
- Yeah. - Robert.
- 海瑟 你没事吧 - 我还好
- Heather, you doing all right? - Hanging in there.
你记得打电话骚扰我的人吗
You know the guy that was calling me all the time?
他又来了 他把东西放在我的信箱里
He started again. And he's putting stuff in my mail again.
那个混蛋或许是看到葬礼新闯
The SOB probably read about the funeral in the papers or something.
王八蛋 你不该受这种气的
Sick mother. It's the last thing you need right now, I'm sure.
这让我梦到佛莱迪
Actually, it's been giving me Freddy nightmares.
等一下
Wait a second, now let me get this straight.
你梦到佛莱迪
You're having nightmares about Freddy?
我演的佛莱迪
As in me?
不 不是你 他更可怕
No, it isn't you. He's scarier.
他
He's....
更黑暗邪恶
Darker? More evil?
对 你怎么知道
Yeah. How did you know?
就说我是胡猜的
Call it a guess.
你猜得很准
Pretty damn good guess.
总之那是我打电话给你的原因
Anyway, what I was calling about was...
你看到剧本了吗
...have you seen any of the script by any chance?
不 剧本没写好前
No. Wes won't show it until he's finished.
他不会拿给任何人看 他是那么告诉我的
At least that's what he told me.
剧本何时会写好
Well, when is it gonna be done?
天知道 他真的很奇怪
Well, the way he's writing, who knows? He's so weird.
我在葬礼上 问他剧本写得如何
I asked him how far he was at the funeral. What did he say?
他说"我只写到 迪伦试着跟上帝接触"
Oh, yeah. "As far as Dylan trying to reach God."
天知道那是什么意思 很奇怪吧
Whatever that means. Weird, huh?
把你的孩子写在剧本里
Putting your kid in the script.
劳勃 你有做恶梦吗
Robert, have you been having nightmares?
我们得谈一谈 不能在电话里谈
Look, we need to talk, but not over the phone.
我能去你家吗
Can I come over?
事实上 海瑟
Um, actually, Heather, uh...
今天我没空
...today's no good. There's, um....
我有事 得去处理一下 约明天吧
There's something I have to finish. Tomorrow maybe, huh?
好吧 明天 我们一早就见面
Okay, tomorrow. But early in the morning.
劳勃 好好保重
And meanwhile, Robert, take care, okay?
对 当然
Yeah. Sure.
该死
Damn it!
一 二 佛莱迪要来抓你了
One, two, Freddy's coming for you
迪伦
Dylan?
三 四 锁好你的门
Three, four, better lock your door
五 六 快去拿十字架
Five, six, grab your crucifix
七 八 彻夜不眠
Seven, eight, better stay up late
迪伦 不要唱那首歌
Dylan. Don't sing that song.
九 十 永远不要睡
Nine, ten, never sleep again
迪伦
Dylan!
住手
Stop it!
不
No!
永远不要睡
Never sleep again.
迪伦
Dylan.
永远不要睡
Never sleep again.
不要
Never sleep ag...
- 对 - 他是我的
- Yes. - Ha-ha-ha. I touched him.
你家族有癫痴病史吗
Any history of epilepsy in your family?
没有
No.
- 糖尿病 - 没有
- Diabetes? - No.
发生过能够刺激他的事吗
Was there a trigger event?
譬如外伤或休克
Trauma, shock?
你没让他看你演过的
You haven't shown him any of the films you've made, have you?
恐怖电影吧
The horror stuff?
他爸爸刚刚过世
His father just passed away.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
但我相信
But I'm convinced...
那些电影会导致不稳定的孩子 出现行为异常
...those films can tip an unstable child over the edge.
不稳定
Unstable?
迪伦不是不稳定 他只是难过
Dylan's not unstable. He's just upset.
过几天我们会知道答案的
We'll run tests and we'll know in a few days.
今晚他一定要留在这里吗
Does he have to stay here overnight?
当然
Absolutely.
迪葛拉菲医生 急诊室
Dr. Degraffey, ER.
还发生了什么事 是我们该知道的吗
Anything more happen we need to know about?
譬如说呢
Well, like what?
有时候小孩子说的话 幻想的事
Sometimes what a child says or fantasizes...
能告诉我们是什么刺激了他
...will give a clue to what ails him.
他意识不清时说了什么话吗
Did he say anything while he was still lucid?
没有
No.
爱因侯医生 237线
Dr. Einhorn, line 237.
他到底是怎么了
What do we have here?
现在还无法判断
Too soon to know for sure.
初期症状显示应该是儿童精神分裂症
The early symptoms point to childhood schizophrenia.
迪伦 你能听到我说话吗
Dylan, can you hear me?
迪伦 你得抗拒到底
Dylan, you have to fight it...
不论是什么东西在追你 你得回到我身边
...whatever it is that's after you, and you gotta come back to me.
你一个人是办不到的 你听到了吗
You can't make it alone. Do you hear?
如果你能听到我说话
If you can hear me,
那么你能告诉我该怎么做能让你觉得安全
then you can tell me what you need to feel safe.
雷斯 你要找它吗
Rex? Is that what you want?
雷斯在家里
Well.... Well, Rex is at home...
你也该回家
...and that's where you should be.
但你得好起来他们才会让你回家
But you gotta get better before they'll let you come home.
你懂吗
Do you understand?
家
Home.
家 没错
Home. Home, that's right.
我要你回家 甜心
That's where I want you, sweetie.
我们离家不远
And you know, we're not that far away.
听着 就在那边
Look. Look, right out there...
过了高速公路说是我们家
...past the freeway is our home.
想要回家
But to get there...
你得离开现在那个地方
...you have to come out from where you are...
他们才会让你回家找雷斯
...so that they'll let you come home to Rex...
还有找我
...and to me.
你该吃药了 小子
Time for your medicine, cowboy.
那是什么
What is that?
能帮他入眠的药
Something to help him sleep.
好吧
Okay.
来吧 非常好
There you go. Yeah, it's good.
来吧
There you go.
一 二 很好
One, two, good.
太好了 真是个好孩子
Good! Attaboy!
睡一下吧
Come on, now lie down and take a little nap.
你也该休息一下 他会没事的
You should get some rest too. He's going to be fine.
我们要做一些检查 然后你就可以回来
We're gonna do some tests and then you can come back later.
麻烦你把那边拉起来
Will you get that other side, please?
我带了一些他的东西
I grabbed his things.
这是他最喜欢的睡衣
These are his favorite pajamas here.
甜心 我得走了
Honey, I've gotta go.
我爱你 迪伦
I love you, Dylan.
记住我说过的话
Remember what I said.
我们会好好照顾他的
We'll take care of everything.
再见
Bye.
醒一醒 小姐
Wake up, lady!
我现在不能失控
Don't Iose it now!
加州理工学院的地质学家估计
Seismologists at Caltech have counted...
目前余震超过三百次
...over 300 of the tremblers so far.
虽然多数震度轻微到我们无法感觉
Though most were too faint for us to feel...
最近本市发生了七次有感地震
...seven have shaken our community in the last two weeks.
科学家推测可能有盲断层
And now scientists are speculating there might be an unknown fault...
通过洛杉矶下方
...running beneath Los Angeles. A fault that could...
这里是英格朗家
Hi. You've reached the Englund residence.
我们出城去了
We're out of town right now.
你可以留言 但我们过一阵子才会回来
You can leave a message if you wish, but, uh, we'll be gone for some time.
我也希望能告诉你剧本的进度 我不知道
I wish I could tell you where this script was going. The fact is I don't know.
晚上我梦到故事 天亮后将它写下来
You know, I dream a scene at night. I write it in the morning.
就是这样
Beyond that, your guess is as good as mine where it's going.
告诉我目前故事的发展
Well, at least tell me what it's about so far.
- 咖啡 - 谢谢
- Coffee. - Thanks.
我可以告诉你 目前我做了什么恶梦
I can tell you what the nightmare's about so far.
故事的主角是这个恶鬼 不论你要怎么称呼它
It's about this entity, whatever you want to call it.
它非常老了
It's old. It's very old.
它以不同的形式存在于不同的时代
It's existed in different forms in different times.
它唯一不变的特质就是它存在的目的
The only thing that stays the same is what it lives for.
到底是什么
What is that?
它要杀害无辜的人
Well, the murder of innocence.
我们还在谈剧本的事 对吧 威斯
This is still a script we're talking about, right, Wes?
对 我想它应该是仍在发生中的恶梦
Yeah, well, I sort of think of it as a nightmare in progress.
在这个仍在发生中的恶梦 这个恶鬼有弱点吗
Well, in this nightmare in progress then, does this thing have any weaknesses?
有时候它会被抓住
Well, it can be captured sometimes.
被抓住 该怎么做呢
Captured? How?
被说故事的人或其他力量抓住
By storytellers, of all things.
偶尔
I mean,
他们会想到一个好故事抓住恶鬼
every so often they imagine a story good enough to sort of catch its essence...
把恶鬼关在故事里
...and then for a while it's held prisoner in the story.
- 就像是瓶中精灵 - 没错
- Like the genie in the bottle. - Exactly. Exactly.
问题是故事会死去
But the problem comes when the story dies.
原因非常多
That can happen in a lot of ways.
它变得太老套
It can get too familiar to people...
或是有人灌水 想把它拿去卖钱
...or somebody waters it down to make it an easier sell.
或是它被完全禁止
You know, or maybe it's just so upsetting to society that it's banned outright.
故事死去时 恶鬼能获得自由
However it happens when the story dies, the evil is set free.
你是说佛莱迪是古老恶鬼
You're saying Freddy is this ancient thing?
对 现代版的
Right. Current version.
十年来他在《半夜鬼上床》系列
And for 10 years, he's been held captive pretty much...
被描绘成佛莱迪的形象
...as Freddy in the Nightmare on Elm Street series...
现在电影系列结束
...but now that the films have ended...
我们的精灵从瓶子里逃出来
...the genie's out of the bottle, Heather.
那是恶梦告诉我的
That's what the nightmares are telling me and that's what I'm writing.
如果佛莱迪从你的剧本里逃走
Well, if Freddy is loose in your script...
他会去哪里
...where's he gonna go?
去另一个时代 换另一种形式
Another age? Another form?
不 梦不是要他那么做
No. That's not what the dreams have him doing though.
他要做什么
What is he doing?
现在他习惯自己是佛莱迪
Well, see, he's sort of gotten used to being Freddy now...
他喜欢我们的时空 他决定跨过界线
...and he likes our time and space, so he's decided to cross over.
离开电影 进入我们的真实世界
Out of films, into our reality.
有人可以阻止他吗
Isn't there somebody who can stop him?
事实上在梦里有一个人
Actually, there is a person in the dreams...
她可以说扮演着守门人的角色
...sort of a gatekeeper, so to speak.
佛莱迪得先过她那一关才能进入我们的世界
Somebody that Freddy has to get by before he can come through into our world.
那个人就是你 海瑟
That person's you, Heather.
- 我 - 是的
- It's me? - Yeah.
为什么是我
But why me?
认真地想起来 这的确有道理
Well, dramatically speaking, it makes perfect sense.
毕竟你饰演南希
You played Nancy, after all.
你是第一个羞辱他的人
You were the first to humiliate him, defeat him.
那是南希 不是我
That was Nancy, Wes, it's not me.
但你给了南希力量
Yeah, but it was you that gave Nancy her strength...
想要逃脱 他得先过你那一关
...so in order to get out he's got to come through you.
他会试着攻击你的弱点
And it's inevitable that he's gonna try to do that at your most vulnerable points.
天啊 威斯 你知道吗
Oh, my God, Wes. Did you know?
那是剧本
Heather, it was a script.
那是梦 我不知道
It was a dream. I didn't know.
你很清楚事情没那么简单
You know damn well it's more than that now.
威斯
Wes.
我们该怎么阻止他
How can we stop him?
我想阻止他的唯一方式就是再拍一部电影
I think the only way to stop him is to make another movie.
我会努力把剧本写完
I swear I'll stay by this computer and write until I finish the script...
但在我写完剧本时 你得做出选择
...but when that time comes, you're gonna have to make a choice.
选择 什么选择
Choice? What kind of choice?
你要不要最后一次 饰演南希
Whether or not you're willing to play Nancy one last time.
(儿童疾病研究)
(美国心理学家)
"许多儿童精神分裂症的症状
"Many of the symptoms of childhood schizophrenia...
都导因于儿童 出现睡眠不足的问题"
...are duplicated in children suffering from sleep deprivation. "
"睡眠不足会产生出神症状
"Sleep deprivation can produce trance-like states...
机械式动作"
... mechanical behavior.... "
我不想睡
I'm not sleepy.
雷斯把我吵醒
Rex woke me u p.
它在对抗有爪子的坏老头
He was fighting the mean old man with the claws.
你不知道是谁打电话骚扰你
You have no idea who this is calling?
我只知道是佛莱迪
Freddy, for all I know.
我演的佛莱迪
As in me?
不 不是你 他更可怕
No, it isn't you. He's scarier.
- 更黑暗邪恶 - 你怎么知道
- Darker? More evil? - How did you know?
他决定跨过界线
He's decided to cross over...
离开电影 进入我们的真实世界
...out of films, into our reality.
永远不要睡
Never sleep again.
恐怖电影界今天发生了悲剧
The world of horror films suffered its own terror today...
两位好莱坞最佳特效人员
...as two of Hollywood's best-known special-effects technicians...
被发现陈尸在空地
... were found dead in a vacant field.
泰伦斯范斯坦跟查尔斯威尔森
Terrance Feinstein and Charles Wilson...
他们在为佛莱迪·克鲁格系列电影
... two special-effects artists reputedly working on a top-secret project...
制作单位进行一项超机密计划
... for the makers of the Freddy Krueger films...
今天早上被发现遭人杀害
... were found brutally slashed to death early this morning.
佛莱迪的手套不见了
Freddy's glove was missing,
警察怀疑凶案发生的原因
and police are speculating the murders were the result...
是因为两天前一位小偷行窃失手痛下毒手
... of a botched theft, which apparently took place two days ago.
警方一直没找到凶器
At this point the murder weapon has not been found...
天啊
Oh, God.
想念我吗
Miss me?
南希
Nancy.
迪伦
Oh, Dylan. Dylan!
现在不是访客时间 你必须了解
There are no visiting hours. You must understand.
不 我不了解 我是他保姆
No, I don't understand. I'm his babysitter.
我是他们家的朋友 我只要看他一眼
I'm a close friend of the family, damn it. I just need to see him for a minute.
- 就一分钟 拜托 - 你得了解
- Sixty seconds. Come on. - You have to understand...
- 我不能让你见他 - 茱莉
- ...I can't let you see him. - Julie?
- 海瑟 - 你在做什么
- Heather. - What are you doing here?
我不知道
I don't know.
我梦到关于迪伦的恶梦
I had this terrible dream about Dylan.
我非来见他不可
I had to come and see him.
你一定以为我疯了
You must think I'm crazy.
不 我不会那么想 他还好吗
No, I don't. Is he all right?
他们不让我进去
I don't know, they wouldn't let me in.
兰根坎普小姐 在这家医院中
Miss Langenkamp, I'm afraid there are no evening visiting hours...
- 晚上没有访客时间 - 他还好吗
- ...in intensive care. - ls he all right?
迪伦吗 他很好
Dylan? He's holding well.
之前他出了一些问题
Earlier, he had some problems.
我们让他使用氧气帐篷
He's in an oxygen tent just now.
天啊
Oh, my God.
海瑟
Heather.
看起来你发生了一些意外 兰根坎普小姐
Seems we've had an accident, Miss Langenkamp.
能让我看一下吗
May I?
你伤得不轻 你怎么受伤的
Those are nasty cuts. How did you get them?
我在地震中受伤
It happened in the earthquake.
我跌倒了
I fell.
我得见迪伦
I need to see Dylan.
等一下 先让我们帮你治疗
Wait a moment. First, let's see about you.
如果再靠近手腕几寸
If these had been a few inches nearer the wrist....
你到底是怎么受伤的
What did you say you cut yourself on?
当时发生地震 我不知道
It was the earthquake, it was dark, I have no idea.
这是新伤口
But these look quite fresh.
没错 我在今晚地震中受伤
They are. It happened in tonight's earthquake.
十五分钟前发生地震
It happened just 15 minutes ago.
你一定感觉到了
You must have felt it.
还好这里没感觉
Guess we lucked out over here.
你儿子很怕一个男人
Your son is apparently terrified of a man...
他认为那个人 要从他的床下爬出来
...someone he thinks is going to come out of his bed.
护士听到他自言自语
One of the nurses heard him talking to himself.
你知道那个人是谁吗
Do you have any idea who that man is, Miss Langenkamp?
我忘记把恐龙玩偶雷斯带来给他
I forgot to bring his dinosaur, Rex.
它能阻止佛莱迪不会爬上他的
He keeps Freddy from coming up out of his...
床
...bed.
你电影里的那个人
The man from your films?
佛莱迪·克鲁格 有爪子的那个人
Freddy Krueger? With the claws?
他害怕那个人
Is that who he's afraid of?
你让你的儿子看你拍的电影 对吧
You have let your child see your films, haven't you?
每个孩子都知道佛莱迪是谁
Every kid knows who Freddy is.
他就跟圣诞老人或金刚一样
He's like Santa Claus or King Kong or....
对
Yes. Well...
很高兴能跟你谈 兰根坎普小姐
...interesting talking with you, Miss Langenkamp.
我希望你能了解
I hope you understand.
我只是担心你儿子的健康
My concerns are simply for the welfare of your son.
他还好吧
How's he doing?
迪伦
Dylan!
甜心 你不该那么做
Honey! You shouldn't do that.
太迟了
Too late.
我差一步就能成功 海瑟
I'm almost there, Heather.
差一步就能成功
Almost there!
爸爸
Daddy!
迪伦
Dylan!
- 救命 - 爸爸
- Help! - Daddy!
医生
Doctor!
别让她进来
Keep her right there!
我们无法再压制他
We can't hold him much longer, doctor.
- 全剂量麻醉药 快点 - 这里没有那么多药
- Full anesthetic. Stat! - We don't have that here, doctor.
我要帮他动刀
No anesthetic, you say. Screw it then, I'm going in.
我不喜欢这个小混蛋一肚子坏水
Little booger's full of something I don't like.
我们得帮他开肠剖肚
Let's get him open.
砍掉他的邪恶
Cut this evil out of him.
不
No!
- 葛洛莉亚 - 他抢走我的儿子
- Gloria! - He's got my baby?
- 谁 - 佛莱迪
- Who? - Freddy!
谁 佛莱迪·克鲁格
Freddy? Who? Freddy Krueger or something?
发生了什么事
What the hell is going on?
佛莱迪抢走我儿子
My baby, Freddy's got my baby. He's got my Dylan.
兰根坎普小姐
Miss Langenkamp. Miss Langenkamp.
我建议你回家休息一下
I suggest you go home and get some rest.
你儿子没事
Your son is fine.
我们送他到楼下 做进一步检查
He's been taken downstairs for further testing.
刚刚他还在这里
But he was just here.
他刚才在这里 你睡着了 我们将他送走
He was here. You fell asleep. We took him.
你似乎很累
You looked so exhausted.
我们不想吵醒你
Frankly, we didn't want to wake you.
而且茱莉陪着他
Besides, the young woman Julie is with him.
她是他的保姆 对吧
That's his babysitter, right?
相信我 没事的
Believe me, everything is fine.
才怪
Everything's not fine.
该死 通知警卫
Damn. Call security.
警卫注意
Security, code yellow to Pediatric Testing.
小儿科检验处黄色通报
这里是管制区
Uh, this is a restricted area.
- 你有通行证吗 - 去你的通行证
- Do you have a pass? - Screw your pass!
没关系 兰根坎普小姐
It's all right. Miss Langenkamp.
- 他在哪里 - 冷静点
- Where is he? - Just stay calm.
我们的小宝贝还好吗
Tell us how our little boy is doing.
事实上他很好 几分钟前他醒了
He's fine, actually. Uh, he just came around about 10 minutes ago.
他有急性睡眠不足的现象
Uh, he seems to be suffering from acute sleep deprivation.
我想她故意不让他好好睡上一个晚上
I don't think she lets him get sleep.
你说什么 他在哪里
What are you saying? Where is he?
海瑟
Heather.
有人想见你
I've got someone here who wants to see you.
茱莉
Julie.
迪伦
Dylan!
甜心 迪伦 你没事吧 儿子
Oh, honey. Oh, Dylan. Are you okay, champ?
我们能去找雷斯吗 坏人越来越接近了
Can we go get Rex now? The bad man's getting awful close.
我知道
I know he is.
我们立刻去找雷斯
We're gonna go get Rex right now.
恐怕迪伦必须待在这里
I'm afraid Dylan should stay here...
等我们查出他的病因 兰根坎普小姐
...until we know what's causing these episodes, Miss Langenkamp.
我相信你会了解
I'm sure you understand.
很好
Good.
听我说
Look, I'll tell you what.
我去把雷斯带过来
I'm gonna go home and get Rex for you right now.
我们家离这里不远
You know that home isn't far from here, right?
- 过高速公路就到了 - 没错
- Right across the freeway. - That's right.
我很快就回来 茱莉会陪你的
So I won't be gone long. And Julie, she's gonna stay right here with you.
那当然
Yeah. You bet.
拜托你快一点 我好想睡
Hurry up, please. I'm sleepy.
我发誓 真的
I promise. Cross my heart.
迪伦 在妈妈回来前
But, Dylan, until Mommy gets back...
不论你做什么事 千万别睡着了
...whatever you do, don't fall asleep.
茱莉 别让他离开你的视线范围
Julie, don't let him out of your sight.
发生了什么事 你的头发变白了
What's going on here? Your hair's turning gray.
茱莉 让他保持清醒
Julie, keep him awake!
懂吗
Understand?
你能跟我们来一下吗
Excuse me, miss, would you come with us for a second?
什么
What? Hey!
你们想做什么
What the hell do you think you're doing? Get your hands off me.
你介意吗 这到底是怎么一回事
Do you mind? What the hell is this?
我只想谈一下 为了迪伦
Just a quick word, Miss Langenkamp, for Dylan's sake.
今天真的很混乱 对吧 兰根坎普小姐
Well, we've had an exciting day, haven't we, Miss Langenkamp?
- 一 二 三 - 你赢了
- One, two, three. One, two, three. - You won.
你能暂时到外面等一下吗
Would you mind stepping outside for just one moment, miss?
我不要 你想做什么
As a matter of fact, I would. What are you doing?
我要帮他打针 让他睡着
It's just a little shot to see that he gets some sleep.
不 他妈妈特别交代过
No. His mother specifically said...
- 我说不行 - 快点
- I said no. - Do it.
- 噢! - 好了
- Ow! - All done.
他很快就会睡着
He'll be asleep in no time.
- 放开我的手 - 大混蛋
- Would you mind letting go of my arm? - You bitch!
你不能那么做
Hey! You can't do that!
我知道那里面装了什么 你知道这里面装了什么吗
Well, I know what's in that one. Do you have any idea what's in this one?
我扎中你时会发生什么事呢
Or what's gonna happen to you when I stick you with it?
我会动手的
And I will.
不 迪伦 我要你保持清醒 好吗
Oh, no. No, no, no, Dylan. I want you to stay awake, okay?
张开眼睛
I want you to keep your eyes open for me, okay? Come on.
兰根坎普小姐
Miss Langenkamp...
你的家族有滥用药物史吗
...has there been any use of recreational drugs in your family?
- 什么 - 或是精神病史
- What? - Or any history of mental disturbance?
- 你到底想问什么 - 别误会
- What are you asking? - Please, don't take it wrong.
如果真的是那样 极有可能
If there was, there's a good chance...
迪伦出现了遗传性健康问题
...Dylan could be suffering from something passed down to him.
你一直被幻觉所扰吗
Have you been suffering from any delusional events, Miss Langenkamp?
你电影里的这个人
This man from your films...
佛莱迪·克鲁格
...Freddy Krueger....
你一直都能看到他吗
Have you been seeing him?
不
No.
- 喂 - 快把钥匙拿过来
- Hello! - Would you get those keys?
迪伦 保持清醒 张开眼睛
Dylan, I want you to stay awake. Come on, stay awake.
- 张开眼睛 - 妈妈在哪里
- Keep your eyes open for me, okay? - Where's Mommy?
她 马上回来
She'll be back. Now, stay awake.
有些药物跟治疗方法 兰根坎普小姐
There are drugs and treatments, Miss Langenkamp.
我们可以安排迪伦到寄养家庭暂时待一阵子
We could put Dylan in foster care for a short while...
让我们好好帮你做检查
...just long enough to run some tests on you.
张开眼睛 加油 保持清醒
Just keep your eyes open. Do that for me, okay?
我要你保持清醒
Come on. Stay awake. Stay awake for me, Dylan.
我要你保持清醒 张开眼睛
I want you to stay awake, okay? Stay awake. Keep your eyes open.
迪伦 怎么了
Dylan, what's the matter?
茱莉 在你的后面
Julie, behind you.
没事啊
There's nothing there.
迪伦 怎么了
Dylan, what's wrong?
迪伦 别闹了 你吓到我
Dylan, stop it. You're scaring me.
迪伦
Dylan?
我要见我儿子
I want my son out of here, right now!
好吧
Very well.
等我们拿到文件后
As soon as we can gather the appropriate papers.
你不了解 如果迪伦睡着了
You don't understand! If Dylan falls asleep...
让我来
I got it.
不
Oh, no!
迪伦 快离开这里
Dylan, get out of here!
快点 迪伦
Get... Dylan!
迪伦 你帮猫咪剥过皮吗
Hey, Dylan, ever play skin the cat?
不
Aah! No! No!
来吧
FREDDY. Come on.
救救我
Help me.
茱莉
Julie!
雷斯
Rex!
发生了什么事
What the hell's going on?
你不能进去 退后
No, miss, you can't go in there. No, get back.
等一下 你不能进去
No, wait, wait. You can't...
警卫注意
Code yellow to Pediatric Testing.
小儿科检验处黄色通报
茱莉
Julie.
我儿子在哪里 他在哪里
Where's my son? Where is he?
你看到我儿子了吗
Have you seen my son?
- 刚刚他还在这里 - 那孩子吗
- He was just here. He was just.... - The boy?
他不可能会跑掉 我们帮他注射安眠药
No way he's going anywhere. He's been heavily sedated.
他不可能保持清醒乱跑
He doesn't have to be awake to be on his feet.
- 什么? - 他在梦游 你这个白痴
- What? - He sleepwalks, you idiot!
他有办法离开医院 该死
He's fully capable of walking out of this hospital! Oh, shit!
- 喂 - 约翰 我需要你帮忙
- Hello? - John, It's Heather. I need your help!
- 为什么 发生了什么事 - 迪伦离开医院
- Why? What happened? - John, Dylan's run away from the hospital.
我不知道他是不是在梦游
I don't know if he's wandering around or headed for the house...
我想佛莱迪在追他 我知道这听起来很疯狂 可是
...but I think Freddy's after him! I know that sounds so crazy, but...
你说的对 真的很疯狂
You're right. That sounds crazy.
天啊
Oh, my God.
迪伦
Dylan!
你知道我们家离这里不远
You know that home isn't far from here.
不 迪伦
No! Dylan!
就在高速公路对面
Right across the freeway.
迪伦
Dylan!
克鲁格 你这个混蛋
Krueger, you bastard!
快来抓我吧
Take me!
迪伦
Dylan!
- 你没事吧 - 发生了什么事
- Are you okay? - Hey, man, is she okay?
我儿子在这里
My son is out here!
迪伦 放开我 迪伦
Dylan! Dylan! Leave me alone! Dylan!
迪伦
Dylan!
- 迪伦 - 对不起
- Dylan? Aah! - Oh, I'm sorry!
发生了什么事 你没事吧
What happened to you? Are you all right?
我没事 你有看到迪伦吗
I'm fine. Have you seen Dylan? Where is he?
放轻松 冷静点 他在那边发生了什么事
Take it easy. Take it easy. Relax. He's right there. What happened?
迪伦 天啊
Oh, Dylan! Oh, God! You're here.
发生了什么事 海瑟 到底发生了什么事
What's going on, Heather? What in the world happened?
- 我知道契斯为什么会死掉 - 你是什么意思
- I know how Chase really died. - What do you mean?
是佛莱迪·克鲁格干的
Fred Krueger did it.
当然
Yeah, sure.
你看到他了 对吧
You saw him, didn't you?
我来抓你了
Coming for you
南希 我们到外面谈
Nancy, let's go outside.
- 迪伦 - 他会没事的
- Dylan. - He'll be all right.
我 马上回来
I'll be right back.
到底发生了什么事 南希
What the hell is going on, Nancy?
为什么你要叫我南希 约翰
Why are you calling me Nancy, John?
为什么你要叫我约翰
Why are you calling me John?
南希 振作一点 别把自己跟那孩子逼疯了
Nancy, pull yourself together before you make yourself and that kid nuts.
约翰
John!
- 你有打电话给劳勃吗 - 劳勃
- Would you call Robert? - Robert?
劳勃英格朗
Robert Englund.
饰演佛莱迪的演员
You know, the guy who plays Freddy.
- 什么佛莱迪 - 佛莱迪·克鲁格
- Freddy who? - Freddy Krueger!
南希 佛莱迪死了
Nancy, Freddy's dead.
不要乱发疯 就跟你妈一样
Now, don't start losing it like your mother did.
我爱你 甜心
I love you, sweetheart.
别忘了那一点
Don't forget that.
我也爱你 爸爸
I love you too, Daddy.
好好休息一下 南希 拜托
Now, get yourself some rest, Nancy. Please.
迪伦
Dylan?
一 二 佛莱迪要来抓你了
One, two, Freddy's coming for you
迪伦
Dylan!
差一点就成功了
Almost there!
爸爸 我跟你讲
Listen, Daddy, I've got a proposition for you.
我要去找这件事的元凶
I'm gonna go and get the guy who did it.
到那里逮捕他 等我将他带出来
And I want you to be there to arrest him when I bring him out, okay?
南希 告诉我是谁干的 我会抓到他 宝贝
Nancy, just tell me who did it. I'll go get him, baby.
是佛莱迪·克鲁格干的 爸爸
Fred Krueger did it, Daddy.
当然
Yeah, sure.
迪伦的安眠药
Dylan's sleeping pills?
告诉我他们怎么找到回家的路
Say how they find their way back home.
那真的很重要
It's important.
面包屑 迪伦
Bread crumbs. Dylan.
太迟了 海瑟
Too late, Heather.
太迟了
Too Iate.
迪伦
Dylan.
加入你
Join you.
你告诉我该怎么加入你
You've given me a way to join you.
太棒了
Yes!
妈妈
Mommy!
迪伦
Dylan!
妈妈
Mommy!
差一点就成功了
Almost there.
她越深入研究
"The more she read...
越了解拿在她自己手上的东西
...the more she realized what she had in her hands...
就是她的生命
...was nothing more or less than her life itself.
她经历跟思索过的一切
That everything she had experienced and thought...
都写在剧本里
... was bound within these pages. "
这不是电影
"There was no movie.
事实上这是
There was only...
她的人生
... her life. "
- 是我 - 迪伦
- It's just me. - Dylan!
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- Are you okay? Are you all right? - Yeah.
- 那个人在哪里 - 我不知道
- Okay. Where's the man? - I don't know.
他抓到我 后来又放了我
He had me, but then he let me go.
来见见你的主宰吧
Meet your maker.
帮小鬼挑个宠物吧 混蛋
Pick a pet for the rug rat, bitch.
去你的
Fuck you!
- 妈妈 - 快离开这里
- Mommy! - Get out of here, Dylan!
看我的
Take this!
快过来 宝贝 我有一些姜饼
Come here, my pretty. I've got some gingerbread for you!
不 迪伦 快跑
No! Dylan, run!
妈妈
Mommy!
抓到你了
Gotcha! Ha!
妈妈
Mommy?
- 妈妈 - 妈妈
- Mommy! - Mommy!
你妈妈在哪里
Now, where's your mommy, piglet, huh? Huh?
一 二 佛莱迪要来抓你了
One, two, Freddy's coming for you
迪伦
Dylan?
妈妈
Mommy!
迪伦
Dylan!
妈妈
Mommy!
来爸爸这边
Come to Papa!
我要吃掉你
Gonna eat you up.
不
No!
迪伦 快离开那里
Dylan! Get out of there!
- 嘿 - 啊
- Hey! - Aah!
不
FREDDY. No!
把他关起来
Push him in!
用力谁
Push!
快跑
Run!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
甜心 甜心
Oh, my... Honey. Honey.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们得救了 坏人死了
We're saved. The witch is dead.
妈妈亲吻着他 他们得救了
And his mother covered him with kisses, and they were safe.
海瑟 多谢你有胆量 最后一次扮演南希
Heather, thanks for having the guts to play Nancy one last time.
至少佛莱迪回到了他应该在的地方
At last Freddy's back where he belongs.
威斯敬上
Regards, Wes.
那是故事吗
Is it a story?
那是故事
Yeah. It's a story.
念给我们听
Read me some.
一开始是张旧板凳
"We open on an old wooden bench.
我们看到大伙跟工具 还有一只脏脏的手
There's fire and tools and a man's grimy hands...
很快地我们发现 那是可怕的爪子
...building what soon is revealed as a gleaming set of claws.
爪子在动
And the claws are moving now...
像是从漫漫恶梦中醒了过来
...as if awakening from a long and unwanted sleep.
那个人将枓动的手平放在桌上
Then the man lays one trembling hand flat upon the table...
跟其他的手放在一起 他拿起又尖又利的刀子
...and with his other, picks up a thick, sharp blade.
在灯光后面
Behind the lights, faces watch from the darkness...
从黑暗中观看的脸孔 准备大笑或恐怖尖叫
...ready to laugh or scream in terror."
《猛鬼街7》
[纪念格雷格·冯希卡]